Oceans rise. Cities fall. Hope survives.
Deep Impact is a action, drama, science fiction film directed by Mimi Leder.
A seven-mile-wide space rock is hurtling toward Earth,
threatening to obliterate the planet.
Now, it's up to the president of the United States to save the world.
He appoints a tough-as-nails veteran astronaut to lead a joint
American-Russian crew into space to destroy the comet before impact.
Meanwhile, an enterprising reporter uses her smarts
to uncover the scoop of the century.
Capt. Spurgeon 'Fish' Tanner, played by Robert Duvall.
Jenny Lerner, played by Téa Leoni.
Leo Biederman, played by Elijah Wood.
Robin Lerner, played by Vanessa Redgrave.
President Tom Beck, played by Morgan Freeman.
Jason Lerner, played by Maximilian Schell.
Deep Impact is a 1998 American science fiction disaster film directed by Mimi Leder, written by Bruce Joel Rubin and Michael
Tolkin, and starring Robert Duvall, Téa Leoni, Elijah Wood, Vanessa Redgrave, Maximilian Schell, and Morgan Freeman.
Steven Spielberg served as an executive producer of this film.
It was released by Paramount Pictures in North America and by
DreamWorks Pictures internationally on May 8, 1998.
The film depicts humanity's attempts to prepare for and destroy a 7-mile (11 km)
wide comet set to collide with Earth and cause a mass extinction.
Deep Impact was released in the same summer as the similarly themed Armageddon, which fared better
at the box office, while astronomers described Deep Impact as being more accurate.
Deep Impact was slightly better received critically than
Armageddon, although both ultimately received mixed reviews.
Deep Impact grossed over $349.5 million worldwide on an $80 million
production budget, becoming the sixth highest-grossing film of 1998.
It was the final film by cinematographer Dietrich
Lohmann, who died before the film's release.
The film explores themes of usa president, nasa,
natural disaster, space mission, comet.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking.